Register of the Poland. Ambasada (United States) Records, 1918-1956
Hoover Institution Archives
- CIRCULARS, 1920-1951
  - Poland, Republic (Box 43.)
    - General, 1945-1951 (Folder 1)
    - Ministerstwo Prac Kongresowych (Ministry of Preparatory Work for the Peace Conference)
      - General, 1945 (Folder 2)
      - "The Economic Importance of the Upper Silesian Coal Fields," 1944 (Folder 3)
      - "Economic Problems of Postwar Germany," January 1945 (Folder 4)
      - "O Nowy Porzadek Rzeczy" (Concerning the New Order of Germany) (Folder 5)
      - "Some Economic Aspects of East Prussia" (Folder 6)
      - "Some Economic Aspects of Opole Silesia" (Folder 7)
      - "Tentative Estimate of the National Wealth of East Prussia and Opole Silesia" (Folder 8)
      - "Tezy w Sprawie Ukladu Wstepnego" (Theses Concerning the Preliminary Arrangements), November 20, 1942 (Folder 9)
      - "Zagadnienie Niemiec" (The Question of Germany) (Folder 10)
      - "Ziemie Wschodnie Polski" (Poland's Eastern Territory), March 1943, and "The Problem of Prussia" (Folder 11)
    - Ministerstwo Spraw Wewnetrznych (Ministry of Internal Affairs)
      - Wydzial Narodowosciowy (Nationalities Section)
        - "Niemiecka Polityka Okupacyjna Na Terenie Bialorusi w Odrebie Panstwa Polskiego" (German Occupation Policy in the Byelorussian Territory Within the Polish State), by Dr. Jozef Rudnicki, February 20, 1945 (Folder 12)
        - "Ziemia Czerwienska Pod Okupacja Niemiecka, Czerwiec 1941 - Czerwiec 1943" (The Czerwien Territory Under the German Occupation, June 1941 -June 1943), by Dr. Jozef Rudnicki, June 17, 1944 (Folder 13)
      - Wydzial Spleczny (Social Section)
        - "Wysiedlenie Polakow Podczas Wojny (The Displacement of Poles During the War), 1944 (Folder 14)
        - Various, 1942-1943 (Box 44., Folder 1)
    - Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Ministry of Foreign Affairs)
      - General circulars
        - 1942 October 21 (Folder 2)
        - 1943 March 10 (Folder 3)
        - 1944 November 15 (organization and personnel of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs) (Folder 4)
        - 1944
          - Holiday greetings from Minister of Foreign Affairs to Polish foreign service personnel (Folder 5)
          - Various circulars sent by the Minister of Foreign Affairs) (Folder 6)
        - 1947 January 16 (from Adam Tarnowski, Minister of Foreign Affairs) (Folder 7)
      - Dyrekcja Spraw Politycznych, Wydzial Wschodni (Directorate of Political Affairs, Eastern Section)
        - "Krajowa Rada Narodowa i Polski Komitet Wyzwolenia Narodowego" (The National Council of the Land and the Polish Committee of National Liberation), November 5, 1944 (Folder 8)
        - "Sytuacja Miedzynarodowa" (The International Situation). Sekretariat Departamentu Dyplomatycznego (Diplomatic Section Secretariat), 1921 (Folder 9-11)
    - Miscellaneous circulars probably distributed by the Polish Government in London
      - Copies of various documents on Polish-Soviet relations, numbered 1 to 272, 1943-1945 (Folder 12-13)
      - "T. Zw. Wcielenie Polskich Ziem Wschodnich do Zwiazku Sowieckego - Warunki i Okolicznosci" (The So-Called Incorporation of the Eastern Polish Territories into the Soviet Union - Conditions and Circumstances), London, August-October 1943 (Box 45., Folder 1)
      - "Ziemie Wschodnie Polski Pod Okupacja Sowiecka" (The Eastern Territories of Poland Under Soviet Occupation), London, September 1943
  - Poland, Peoples Republic. Polish Research and Information Service. "Cultural Life in Poland," January 1949 (Folder 3)
- MEMORANDA, 1918-1947
  - Associations Regionales de la Pologne Orientale. Memorandum to the delegates of the United Nations General Assembly, January 26, 1946 (Box 45., Folder 4)
  - Ciechanowski, Jan, Ambassador
    - Memoranda and notes submitted to the U.S. Department of State, 1941-1945 (Folder 5)
    - Memorandum to President Harry S. Truman, (delivered by George Creel), June 5, 1945 (Folder 6)
    - Various memoranda
      - 1942-1945 (Folder 7)
      - 1944-1946 (Folder 8)
  - Jewish emigration (Folder 9)
  - Karski, Jan, "Structural Changes in the Polish Underground State," April 4, 1944 (Folder 10)
  - Lipski, Jozef, Ambassador, "Observations on German Economic Conceptions," January 8, 1941 (Folder 11)
  - "Memorandum," London, February 1947 (Folder 12)
  - Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych. Memorandum of April 1940 sent from Angers to the Polish Government in Paris on the goals of the Polish Embassy in Washington, D.C., including draft budget (Folder 13)
  - Poland, Republic. Government in Exile, London. Memorandum submitted to the Chairman of the Conference of United Nations in San Francisco, London, April 1945 (transmitted by Ambassador Ciechanowski). With accompanying letter of Ambassador Ciechanowski, dated April 19, 1945 (Folder 14)
  - Polish-German relations, 1918-1931 (Folder 15)
  - Polish-Soviet relations, 1942 (Folder 16)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) (Folder 17)
  - Wherry, Kenneth S., memorandum to Edward R. Stettinius, March 31, 1945 (Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous memoranda (Box 46., Folder 1)
- PARAPHRASES OF CONVERSATIONS, 1931-1944
  - Ambassador - Various U.S. Department of State officials, 1931-1933 (Box 46., Folder 2)
  - Zaleski, August - Welles, Sumner, Paris, March 9, 1940 (Folder 3)
  - Raczynski, Edward, Count - Eden, Anthony, Sir, et al., 1940-1942 (Folder 4)
  - Kot, Stanislaw - Molotov, V. - Stalin, J. V., and Sikorski, W., General - Anders, General - Molotov, V. - Stalin, J. V. (Polish-Soviet talks, 1941) (Folder 5)
  - Ciechanowski, Jan, Ambassador - Welles, Sumner, May 27, 1943 (Folder 6)
  - Ciechanowski, Jan, Ambassador - Berle, Adolf A., Jr., September 24, 1943 (Folder 7)
  - Senyshyn, A., Bishop - Jedrzejewski, Klemens, Professor, May 15, 1944 (Folder 8)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1936-1956
  - Bilmanis, Alfred, Dr.
    - The Church in Latvia, 1943 (Box 46., Folder 9)
    - Dictionary of Events in Latvia, 1946 (Folder 10)
    - The Legend of the Baltic Barrier States, 1946 (Folder 11)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry
    - "Some Truths About Poland," reprinted from The American Mercury, February 1945 (Folder 12)
    - "Will Stalin Dictate an Eastern Munich?" reprinted from The American Mercury, March 1944 (Folder 13)
  - Documents Concerning the Elections Held in Romania on November 19, 1946, By the Soviet Imposed Communist Regime (Folder 14)
  - Dziennik Ustaw (Journal of Laws)
    - March 17, 1939, No. 20 (photocopies) (Folder 15)
    - April 30, 1949 (Folder 16)
    - June 28, 1951 (Folder 17)
    - December 31, 1952 (Folder 18)
  - "Human Rights in Romania," Romanian National Committee, Washington, D.C., September 1949 (Folder 19)
  - "Kwestya Litewska w Prasie Polskiej" (The Lithuanian Question in the Polish Press), Warsaw, 1905 (original and photocopy) (Folder 20)
  - Latvian Information Bulletin, Latvian Legation, Washington, D.C., March 1947, June 1950, November 18, 1950 (Folder 21)
  - Lednicki, Waclaw, "Russia and Her Culture," reprint, New Europe, No. 10-11, 1941, with dedication by the author (Folder 22)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, "Yalta Aftermath," reprint, American Affairs, July 1945 (Folder 23)
  - Lithuanian Bulletin, Lithuanian American Council, Vols. IV-V, Nos. 1-3, October 1946, January-February 1947 (Folder 24)
  - New York Journal-American, reprint, photos of war damage in Warsaw, April 4, 1946 (Folder 25)
  - Parliamentary Debates, London, 1944 (Folder 26)
  - The Polish Elections, with letter from T. Romer to Ambassador Ciechanowski, January 18, 1947, London, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Polska Na Morzach (Poland on the Seas), March-May 1946 (Folder 2)
  - Polskie Doswiadczenia Powstancze (Polish Insurgent Experiences), Warsaw, 1944 (Folder 3)
  - Religious Freedom and the Church-State Agreement, Polish Research and Information Service, New York, May 1950 (Folder 4)
  - Seyda, Marian, Dr., "Poland and Germany and the Postwar Reconstruction of Europe," September 1942 (Folder 5)
  - Sprawy Polskie, London, March 1952 (Folder 6)
  - United States government, 1946 (Folder 7)
  - United States. Office of War Information, Tale of a City, 1947 (Folder 8)
  - W Obronie Wolnosci i Niepodleglosci Rzeczypospolitej Poskiej (For Freedom and Independence of Poland), Documents, January-July 1947, London (Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-1956 (Folder 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1919-1952
  - Amerasia Case, 1950 (Box 47., Folder 11)
  - American Slav Congress, 1942 (Folder 12)
  - American States
    - VII International Conference, Montevideo, 1933 (Folder 13)
    - VIII International Conference, Lima, 1938 (Folder 14)
  - Antarctica, 1939 (Folder 15)
  - Armament, 1934-1938 (Folder 16)
  - Athenagoras I, 1948-1949 (Folder 17)
  - Aviation, International, 1936-1937 (Folder 18)
  - Baltic States
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 19)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 48., Folder 1)
    - 1939-1944 (Folder 2)
    - 1941-1949 (Folder 3)
    - 1943-1944
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Materials from the office of K. Jedrzejewski (Folder 5)
  - Berlin, Polish Embassy
    - Evacuation, September 2, 1939. Note from Auswaertiges Amt to Polish Embassy (Folder 6)
    - Events from August 21 to September 1, 1939. List, by Ambassador J. Lipski (Folder 7)
  - Borders, Polish
    - General, 1925-1927 (Folder 8)
    - Eastern, 1917-1944 (Folder 9)
    - Hungarian and Czech (Box 49., Folder 1)
    - "Zagadnienie Granic w Swietlie Cywilizacji" (The Problem of Borders in World Civilization), by Seweryn Kamienski, 1944 (Folder 2)
  - Byelorussia, 1925-1929 (Folder 3)
  - Central and East European organizations, 1940-1947 (Folder 4)
  - Chile - Emigration and Immigration. Zwiazek Slowianski (Slavic Union), 1942 (Folder 5)
  - Churches
    - General. Materials from the papers of K. Jedrzejewski (Folder 6)
    - Orthodox
      - General, 1941-1944 (Folder 7)
      - Poland
        - 1934-1935 (Folder 8)
        - 1936-1937 (Folder 9)
    - Protestant, in Poland, 1933-1937 (Folder 10)
    - Roman Catholic
      - General, 1944-1945 (Box 50., Folder 1)
      - "The Catholic Church and the Curzon Line," by S. Kamienski, 1945 (Folder 2)
      - Clergy, 1941-1944 (Folder 3)
      - Gawlina, J., Bishop, 1944 (Folder 4)
      - Persecution, Poland, 1949 (Folder 5)
      - Pius XII, Pope, 1943 (Folder 6)
    - USSR
      - General, 1927-1943 (Folder 7)
      - Persecution (Folder 8)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1949 (Folder 9)
  - Ciechanowski, Jan, honorary doctorate, Georgetown College, 1948 (Folder 10)
  - Commission for Religious Affairs (Folder 11)
  - Communism
    - Communist International (Comintern), 1929-1938 (Folder 12)
    - Influences in the U.S., 1928-1945 (Folder 13)
    - International communism, 1938 (Folder 14)
    - Movement, Communist, in the U.S. and Canada, 1940 (Folder 15)
    - United States, 1943-1950 (Folder 16)
    - Miscellany (Folder 17)
  - Consular affairs
    - Citizenship (Folder 18)
    - Personal data, Pszczynski, Prince and Professor Oscar Lange, 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Count, "The Future of Europe and America," July 4, 1941 (Folder 20)
  - Council for Resettlement of Polish Refugees, London, March 1947 (Folder 21)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 51.)
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1921 (Folder 1)
      - 1923-1924 (Folder 2)
      - 1942-1951 (Folder 3)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Relations with, Polish
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
        - 1935 (Folder 6)
      - Russia and the Little Entente, 1937 (Folder 7)
      - Spisz and Orawa (Folder 8)
      - Teschen (Cieszyn) (Folder 9)
  - Czerwinski, W., "Free Poland," March 27, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Danzig (Gdansk)
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 11)
      - 1920 (Box 52., Folder 1)
      - 1921-1922 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1922-1925 (Folder 4)
      - 1925-1927 (Folder 5)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Free City of Danzig Citizens Committee in the U.S.A., 1941-1943 (Folder 6)
      - Political situation
        - 1930 (Folder 7)
        - 1932 (Folder 8)
      - Port of, 1933 (Folder 9)
  - Dean, Vera M. (Folder 10)
  - Debts, Polish, to U.S.
    - 1926-1929 (Folder 11)
    - 1929-1933 (Box 53., Folder 1)
    - 1930-1931 (Folder 2)
    - 1932 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 5)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 6)
    - 1936-1937 (Folder 7)
  - Disarmament, 1931-1935 (Box 54., Folder 1-6)
  - Disarmament, 1931-1935 (Box 55., Folder 1-2)
  - Displaced persons, 1946-1949 (Folder 3-4)
  - East (Far East), 1922-1938 (Folder 5-6)
  - Ehrlich, Henryk and Alter, Victor (Folder 7)
  - Emigration and immigration
    - German emigre activity, 1942-1944 (Box 56., Folder 1)
    - Polish
      - General, 1935-1937 (Folder 2)
      - "Free Poles and Their Political Life," November 1948 (Folder 3)
      - Brazil, 1938 (Folder 4)
      - United States
        - General, 1938 (Folder 5)
        - Kosciuszko and Pulaski commemorations, 1950 (Folder 6)
        - Political activity, 1944 (Folder 7-8)
    - Young Russia Movement, 1942 (Folder 9)
  - Espionage, German, 1941 (Folder 10)
  - Estonia, 1945, 1951 (Folder 11)
  - Europe, Partition of, 1945 (Folder 12)
  - European Recovery Program, 1948-1949 (Folder 13)
  - Filipowicz, Tytus, correspondence regarding his term as Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Cuba, 1930-1933. Includes letters signed by I. Moscicki and A. Zaleski (Folder 14)
  - Finances and credit
    - General, 1932-1937 (Folder 15)
    - Financial negotiations, 1926-1927 (Folder 16)
    - Financial negotiations, 1926-1927 (Box 57., Folder 1-4)
    - German-Canadian loan agreements, 1936 (Folder 5)
    - Finland, 1942-1944 (Folder 6)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (1944) (Folder 7)
  - France, 1939-1949 (Folder 8)
  - Galicia
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1921 (Folder 9)
      - 1921-1922 (Box 58., Folder 1)
      - 1921-1923 (Folder 2-7)
      - 1921-1923 (Box 59., Folder 1-2)
      - 1924 (Folder 3)
      - 1925 (Folder 4)
      - 1925-1926 (Folder 5)
    - Sheptytskyi, Andrii, Metropolitan (Folder 6-7)
  - Gdynia, 1932-1933 (Folder 8)
  - General Sikorski Historical Institute, 1945-1953 (Folder 9)
  - Genoa Conference, 1922 (Folder 10)
  - Germany
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 11)
      - 1920 (Folder 12)
      - 1921 (Box 60., Folder 1)
      - 1921-1924 (Folder 2)
      - 1925 (Folder 3)
      - 1926-1927 (Folder 4)
      - 1927-1928 (Folder 5)
      - 1930 (Folder 6)
      - 1931-1932 (Folder 7-8)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 61., Folder 1)
      - 1941-1944 (Folder 2)
      - 1941-1947 (Folder 3)
      - 1942-1951 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1944 (Folder 6)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Borders with, 1931-1935 (Folder 7)
      - Disarmament of, 1944 (Box 62., Folder 1)
      - East Prussia, 1922, 1932 (Folder 2)
      - Finances, 1933 (Folder 3)
      - German-Bolshevik agitation, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
      - Mazury and Warmja, 1920-1922 (Folder 5)
      - Negotiations with, 1920-1922 (Folder 6)
      - Non-aggression pact with, 1934 (Folder 7)
      - Pacts of Guarantee (Folder 8)
      - Pomorze (Folder 9)
      - Population, Polish, 1939 (Folder 10)
      - Postwar - Fischer, Ruth, "Memorandum ueber die Zukunft des deutschen Nationalismus und die wahrscheinlichste Variante der russischen Politik in nach-Hitler Deutschland" (Memorandum on the Future of German Nationalism and the Most Probable Variant of Russian Policy in Post-Hitler Germany), n.d. (Folder 11)
      - Relations with, 1921 (Folder 12)
  - Gibson, Hugh, address, November 11, 1946 (Folder 13)
  - Great Britain
    - General, 1947-1949 (Folder 14)
    - Parliament debates, 1944 (Folder 15)
  - Greek loan, 1947 (Folder 16)
  - Haller, Jozef, General - Visit to the United States, 1940 (Folder 17)
  - Hungary, 1943-1953 (Folder 18)
  - Insurance - Poland, 1945 (Folder 19)
  - Inter-allied information groups, 1942 (Box 63., Folder 1-2)
  - International organization, Postwar
    - 1942-1943 (plans) (Folder 3)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 4-5)
  - International Refugee Organization, 1944-1948 (Folder 6-7)
  - Jedrzejewski, Klemens, Professor, various papers, 1943-1944 (Folder 8)
  - Jews
    - Chronological file
      - 1937 (Folder 9)
      - 1937-1947 (Box 64., Folder 1)
      - 1940-1944 (Folder 2)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
      - 1942 (Folder 4)
      - 1943 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1943 (Box 65., Folder 1)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Emigration
        - 1936-1938 (Folder 3)
        - 1937 (Folder 4)
      - Germany
        - 1933 (Folder 5-6)
        - 1936 (Folder 7)
      - Poland (Box 66.)
        - 1920-1926 (Folder 1)
        - 1933-1934 (Folder 2)
        - 1933-1937 (Folder 3)
        - 1936-1937 (Folder 4)
        - 1937 (Folder 5)
        - 1945 (Folder 6)
      - Refugees, 1938-1939 (Folder 7-8)
      - United States (Box 67.)
        - General
          - 1933-1936 (Folder 1)
          - 1940 (Folder 2)
          - 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
        - "The Jewish Problem and the United States," by M. Glaser, January 18, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - Jurasz, Anthony (Folder 5)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - 1941-1949 (Folder 6-7)
    - 1948-1952 (Folder 8)
  - Kersten, Charles J., Senator, 1951 (Box 68., Folder 1)
  - Komitet Narodowy Amerykanow Polskiego Pochodzenia (National Committee of Americans of Polish Descent), 1943-1949 (Folder 2)
  - Kravchenko, Victor A. (Folder 3)
  - Lange, Oscar, Professor (Folder 4)
  - Latvian Legation in Washington, D.C., "Latvia and the Soviet Union," January 1947 (Folder 5)
  - League of Nations
    - Chronological file
      - 1919-1921 (Folder 6)
      - 1923 (Folder 7)
      - 1925-1926 (Folder 8)
      - 1926-1930 (Folder 9)
      - 1927-1928 (Folder 10)
      - 1936 (XVIIth session) (Folder 11)
    - Alphabetical file
      - American League of Nations Proposal, 1933 (Folder 12)
      - Chaco War, 1934-1935 (Folder 13)
      - European unity, 1929-1930 (Folder 14)
      - Indigent foreign citizens, Convention on care of (Folder 15)
      - International Bureau of Labor, 1933-1937 (Folder 16)
      - League of Nations Council. Minutes of meetings
        - 65th session, 1931 (Folder 17)
        - 67th session, 1932 (Folder 18)
      - Minorities, 1933-1935 (Folder 19)
      - Permanent Court of International Justice, 1935-1945 (Folder 20)
      - Poland, Re-election of (Folder 1)
      - Polish delegation, 1920-1921 (Folder 2)
      - Refugees, Aid for, 1936 (Folder 3)
      - Relations of individual nations to, 1934 (Folder 4)
  - Lend-Lease Administration
    - Aid for Poles in the USSR, 1942 (Folder 5-10)
    - Aid for Poles in the USSR, 1942 (Box 70., Folder 1-3)
    - Requisitions
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 4-6)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 71., Folder 1-4)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Folder 5)
  - Lithuania
    - Chronological file
      - 1927 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1928 (Box 72., Folder 1-2)
      - 1931 (Folder 3)
      - 1936 (Folder 4)
      - 1941 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1942 (Folder 7)
      - 1943 (Folder 8-9)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 73., Folder 1)
      - 1944 (Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical file
      - German agitation, 1920 (Folder 3)
      - Negotiations with, 1921 (Folder 4)
      - Vilnius (Wilno), 1920-1922 (Folder 5)
      - Waterways, Lithuanian and Byelorussian, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - London Naval Disarmament Conference, 1936 (Folder 7)
  - Marine Transport and Litigation Agreements, 1943 (Folder 8)
  - Maritime affairs, 1937 (Folder 9)
  - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw
    - General, 1945-1950 (Folder 10)
    - Moscow visit, 1944 (Folder 11)
    - Washington visit, 1944-1948 (Folder 12-13)
  - Mindszenty, Cardinal, 1949 (Box 74., Folder 1)
  - Minorities, 1920-1936 (Folder 2-4)
  - National Committee for Free Europe, 1949-1952 (Folder 5)
  - North Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Folder 6)
  - Orlemanski, Stanislaw, Father (Folder 7)
  - Paderewski, Ignance Jan, Death of, 1941 (Folder 8-10)
  - Peace treaties, 1919-1921 (Folder 1)
  - Personnel, Diplomatic and state, 1937 (Folder 2)
  - Pilsudski, Jozef, Marshal, Death of, 1926-1937 (Folder 3-5)
  - Poland
    - Chronological file
      - 1943-1946 (Folder 6)
      - 1944-1950 (Folder 7)
    - Alphabetical file
      - Armed forces
        - General
          - 1939 December (Folder 8)
          - 1942-1944 (Folder 9)
        - Bank Polski gold, 1942-1944 (Folder 10)
        - Canada, Polish forces in, 1940-1941 (Box 76., Folder 1-2)
        - Lend-lease, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
        - Personnel, recruits from the U.S., etc., 1942-1943 (Folder 4)
        - Prisoners of war, 1941-1945 (Folder 5)
        - USSR, Polish forces formed in, 1941-1944 (Folder 6)
      - Commerce
        - Colonies and raw materials, 1937-1938 (Folder 7-8)
        - Germany (Box 77.)
          - Commercial relations with, 1929-1930 (Folder 1)
          - Credit agreements, 1938-1939 (Folder 2)
        - Wool and cotton, 1944-1945 (Folder 3)
      - Constitution, 1944 (Folder 4)
      - Economy, 1933-1936 (Folder 5)
      - Finances and credit, 1936-1944 (Folder 6)
      - Foreign relations
        - Chronological file
          - 1931 (Folder 7)
          - 1936 (Folder 8)
          - 1937 (Folder 9)
          - 1938 (Folder 10)
          - 1940-1941 (Folder 11)
          - 1943 (Box 78., Folder 1)
        - Alphabetical file
          - Chile - Polish-Chilean Permanent Conciliation Commission, 1935-1937 (Folder 2)
          - Czechoslovakia - Commercial and customs agreements with the U.S., 1937-1938 (Folder 2A)
          - France, 1945 (Folder 3)
          - Germany, 1933-1939 (Folder 4)
          - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR)
            - 1939-1943 (Folder 5)
            - 1941-1942 (Folder 6)
            - 1942 (Folder 7)
            - 1943 (Folder 8-9)
            - 1943 (Box 79., Folder 1-5)
            - 1944 (Folder 6-7)
            - 1944 (Box 80., Folder 1-3)
            - 1945 (Folder 4-5)
      - Government (Polish Republic)
        - Chronological file
          - 1923-1949 (Folder 6-7)
          - 1940 (Angers-London) (Box 81., Folder 1)
          - 1940-1945 (London) (Folder 2)
          - 1941-1945 (Folder 3)
        - Alphabetical file
          - Interim Treasury Committee, 1945 (Folder 4)
          - Ministry of Finance, 1941 (Folder 5)
          - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
            - 1925-1937 (Folder 6)
            - 1928-1937 (Folder 7)
          - Ministry of Preparatory Work concerning the Peace Conference, 1942-1944 (Folder 8)
          - Presidency, 1939-1940 (Folder 9)
          - President's speech, 1945 (Folder 10)
      - Government (Polish People's Republic - Lublin Government)
        - Chronological file
          - 1943-1945 (Folder 11)
          - 1944-1945 (Folder 12)
          - 1943-1947 (Box 82., Folder 1)
          - 1945 (Folder 2-4)
        - Alphabetical file
          - Elections in Poland and Allies' attitude toward, 1945-1947 (Folder 5)
          - Internal affairs, 1919-1922 (Folder 6-7)
          - International position
            - Jedrzejewski, Klemens, "Polska w Systemie A-M (Arktyk-Mediterraneum)" (Poland in the A-M (Arctic-Mediterranean) System), 1943 (Folder 8)
            - Raczynski, Edward, Count, "Poland as a Factor of European Integration," 1942 (Folder 9)
          - Polish Underground Administration, despatches received by the London government, August-November, 1944 (Folder 10)
  - Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences in America, 1952 (Folder 11)
  - Polish Interorganization Council, Third Convention, Chicago, 1938. Minutes (Box 83., Folder 1)
  - Polish Labour Group, 1943 (Folder 2)
  - Polish-American Agreement of Mutual Aid, 1942 (Folder 3)
  - Polish-American Congress, 1944-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Polish-American Council (Rada Polonii Amerykanskiej), 1942 (Folder 5-6)
  - Polish-American Workers' Council (Polsko-Amerykanska Rada Robotnicza), Chicago, 1944 (Folder 7)
  - Polish-American organizations, 1944-1945 (Folder 8)